☰

✕

Privacy Policy
==============

You agree to be subject to the Privacy Policy and the Terms and Conditions by using this website and any service associated with it. You also agree that the Privacy Policy and the Terms and Conditions apply to any email that we send to you either as a part of the service or from when you signup for a newsletter.

We have adopted this privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) to explain what information may be collected on our Website, how we use this information, and under what circumstances we may disclose the information to third parties. This Privacy Policy applies to pilotinstitute.com, learn.pilotinstitute.com, community.pilotinstitute.com, all Teachable and Circle pages, and any mobile applications.

This Privacy Policy, together with the Terms and Conditions posted on our Website, set forth the general rules and policies governing your use of our Website. Depending on your activities when visiting our Website, you may be required to agree to additional terms and conditions.

Website Visitors
----------------

Like most website operators, Pilot Institute collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. Pilot Institute’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how Pilot Institute’s visitors use its website and for marketing purposes. From time to time, Pilot Institute may release non-personally-identifying information e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

Pilot Institute also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, email addresses, and payment information for logged in users, for users signing up for courses or our community, and for people who use our applications or other tools. All information that’s collected including non-personally and personally identifying information can be shared with third parties for any business purpose including advertising. Information is shared with Google Signals to enable better performance tracking.

Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information
-----------------------------------------------

Certain visitors to Pilot Institute’s websites choose to interact with Pilot Institute in ways that require Pilot Institute to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that Pilot Institute gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who sign up for a blog at http://pilotinstitute.com to provide a username and email address. We also ask for names, email addresses, and payment information for course payers in addition to other possible information.

Security
--------

The security of your Personal Information is important to us, but remember that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure. While we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personal Information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

Advertisements and Marketing
----------------------------

Ads appearing on our website may be delivered to users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. Pilot Institute also uses cookies for a variety of purposes. We may get data from and share data with 3rd parties about you to advertise and market to you about this website and our products and services.

Pilot Institute may work with 3rd parties for marketing and advertising purposes. We may pay them or otherwise get access to information about you. Your information may be shared to or by a 3rd party.

If you signed up for a newsletter or a course or used our apps or a quiz, you give us the right to email you. Emails may contain sponsored links, marketing, advertising, and other promotional material. You can unsubscribe at any time.

Links To External Sites
-----------------------

Our Service may contain links to external sites that are not operated by us. If you click on a third party link, you will be directed to that third party’s site. We strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy and terms and conditions of every site you visit.

We have no control over and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies or practices of any third party sites, products or services.

Remarketing and Data Collection
-------------------------------

Pilot Institute uses remarketing services to advertise on third party websites (including Google, Facebook, Microsoft, and more) to previous visitors to our site. It could mean that we advertise to previous visitors who have done something on our site, for example using the contact form to make an enquiry. This could be in the form of an advertisement on the Google search results page, or a site in the Google Display Network. When you visit Pilot Institute’s websites, third-party vendors, including but not limited to Google, Facebook, Microsoft, TikTok and others use cookies, session tokens, and/or server-side tracking to better understand visitors and for marketing/advertising purposes. Of course, any data collected will be used in accordance with our own privacy policy in addition to the third party’s privacy policies. Pilot Institute also uses a variety of services on our website. These include Facebook’s chat plugin, Helpscout, Mailchimp, and Trustpilot. You agree that Pilot Institute may share any information we have with these services.

Additionally, Pilot Institute utilizes Google Analytics and Posthog for event-based analytics.

Personally-Identifying Information
----------------------------------

Pilot Institute discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to employees, contractors, and other affiliated organizations or 3rd parties including but not limited to Teachable and Circle (for our community) for business purposes including marketing, advertising, and more. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using Pilot Institute’s website, you consent to the transfer of such information to them.

If you are a registered user of pilotinstitute.com or its affiliated Teachable account and have supplied your email address, Pilot Institute may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with Pilot Institute and our products. If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users.

Pilot Institute also uses a quizzing platform called QuizBank. Your quizzing data is stored so that personalized studying tips can be shown to you. You will be able to see which topics in the class you are strongest and weakest at. Pilot Institute may collect user data and feedback with Hotjar to improve our products.

Aggregated Statistics
---------------------

Pilot Institute may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its website. Pilot Institute may display this information publicly or provide it to others.

Affiliate Disclosure
--------------------

This site uses affiliate links and does earn a commission from certain links. This does not change the price you may pay.

Cookies
-------

To enrich and perfect your online experience, Pilot Institute uses “Cookies” and similar technologies and services to display personalized content, appropriate advertising, and store your preferences on your computer. These cookies may be set by 3rd parties as well.

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, which the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Pilot Institute uses cookies, session tokens, and other identifiers to help, among other things, Pilot Institute identify and track visitors, their usage of Pilot Institute websites and applications, and their website access preferences. Pilot Institute visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using Pilot Institute’s websites, with the drawback that certain features of Pilot Institute’s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies. Session tokens and identifiers may be created by or shared with third parties.

By continuing to navigate our website without changing your cookie settings, you hereby acknowledge and agree to Pilot Institute’s use of cookies. By using our website or services you also agree that we can use session tokens and other identifiers.

E-commerce
----------

Those who engage in transactions with Pilot Institute – by purchasing Pilot Institute’s services or products, are asked to provide additional information, including as necessary the personal and financial information required to process those transactions. Pilot Institute does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described above. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

Pilot Institute also shares information with our community platform, Circle. Information about your class enrollments, whether you have graduated, if you received a perfect score on your exam, and more can be listed on on your profile. Other members can search for your profile. Additionally, Pilot Institute has a leaderboard for member participation in the community. This leaderboard may be publicly accessible.

Privacy Policy Changes
----------------------

Pilot Institute may change its Privacy Policy from time to time at our sole discretion. Pilot Institute encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.

Contact Information
-------------------

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us via [\[email protected\]](https://pilotinstitute.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

Mon-Saturday 8am-5pm MST

[\[email protected\]](https://pilotinstitute.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

##### Navigation

##### Company

##### Stay Connected

© Copyright 2024 Pilot Institute. All Rights Reserved.

Black Friday Sale - Happening Now
